Guide to the Harold E. Klein papers, 1980-1993.
Klein, Harold E. papers
- Missionary Addresses -- Thailand, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  Missionary Addresses in Thailand
- Stephen Morse, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  Request for Relief Assistance for Kachin Refugees along the Sino-Kachin Frontier by Stephen Morse
  Press Release From The Kachin Independence Organization (KIO)
  Letters to and from Stephen Morse
  Burma Press Summary
  Steve and Linda Morse Newsletter
  Photocopied Pictures of Dr. Stephen Morse and Friends
  Statement by U Win Mra at the meeting of the Working Group on Indigenous Populations
- Mon State Reports, 1991-1993 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  Letters from the New Mon State Party to President Bush and other people in power
  Requests for international assistance in Burma
- U. N., 1987-1992 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  Letters of Petition to U. N. Secretary-General on Human Rights Problems in Burma
  Statement of the Burma Government Delegation against the minorities’ accuses
- U.N. working group on Indigenous populations, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  Statements of the National Democratic Front (NDF) and the Karen National Union on the current situation in Burma
  Documents of the U.N. Working Group on Indigenous Populations on the problems in Burma
  Documents of World Council of Indigenous Peoples
  The U. N. document on situation of human rights in Myanmar for General Assembly, 1992
- Letters from Germany, 1982-1990 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  Letters from Germany, Italy, London, and Stockholm
- Friends of Burma, 1987-1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  Friends of Burma Newsletter published by A Committee of First Baptist Church
  Directory of humanitarian organizations in Burma
- Kachinland Atrocities, 1987-1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  Reports of Kachin Independence Army
  Documents of Central Committee, Kachin Independence Organization
  Friendship between Gen. Mya and Opium King Hkun Sa
  Report on Burmese soldiers raping a Kachin girl
- The Karen National Union (KNU), 1986-1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  Statements by The Karen National Union presented to foreign organizations
  Documents of KNU
  Statements by refugees
  A document concerning the Negotiations between KNU and SLORC
- Senator Lugar, 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  Letters to and from Senator Richard Lugar
- Saw Tamla Wah, 1989-1992 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  Letters from Saw T. Wah describing the ruthlessness of Burmese government
  Letter to President Bush
- The Karens of Burma: Their Search for Freedom and Justice (Box 3, Folder 22)
  Research conducted by H. E. Klein on The Karens
- Lawrence Trapp, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  Letter to L. R. Trapp from Lao People’s National United Liberation Front
  Treaty to free Karen State, Kampuchea, Laos and Vietnam from the domination of any foreign power
- UNESCO / Human Rights, 1986-1994 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  Principle of Human Rights
  Reports on situation of human rights in Burma to United Nations and UNESCO
  "Human Rights Violations Committed by Units/Personnel of Burma’s Army," 1992-1993 (Report)
  "Contacts With Burma, 1935-1949: A Personal Account," by John F. Cady (Papers in International Studies, Southeast Asia Series No. 61, Ohio University)
- Rev. Dennis Tidwell, 1983-1991 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  Letters to and from Dennis Tidwell
  Elephant Express (Newsletter), Tribal News from Thailand’s North
- Economic Situation in Burma, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  News from newspapers concerning Burma’s economic situations
- William Thomas, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  Letters to and from William M. Thomas, Member of Congress
- Walter Taylor -- USNWR, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  Letters to and from the Editors of U.S. News
- Robert H. Taylor, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  Letters to and from Dr. Robert H. Taylor, School of Oriental and African Studies
- Task Force for Asian Freedom, 1985-1987 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  Lao Hmong Freedom Fighters
  Statement by the Karen National Union and the National Democratic Front
  Charter of the Asian Pacific Anti-Communist League
  Letter to H. Ross Perot from L. R. Trapp
  Proposal for Support of Hmong Freedom Fighters
- H. Anthony Stonor, 1982-1993 (Box 3, Folder 31A-B)
  Letters from H. A. Stonor
  Works of H. A. Stonor on Burma’s politics
  Letters from the Kachin Independence Organization
  U Aung San, Who killed him --- and why?
  Letter from Stonor to U. K. House of Commons arguing that the U.K. should support the ethnic groups in Burma who were the allies of the British army in the Second World War
  The returning letters from U.K. Government
- Situations of politics, wars, and drug trafficking in Burma, 1978-1991 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  National Security Council documents on activities of James Gritz, U. S. Army (Retired)
  Letter from National Democratic Front
- Stephen J. Solarz, 1987-1993 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  Letters to and from S. J. Solarz, Member of House of Representatives
  Contents of National Democratic Front
  Declaration of the National Democratic Front
  News on Burma
  Congressional Record on Burma
  Statement of Senator Daniel Patrick Moynihan
  Statement by Dr. Exra Solomon to urge congress to provide humanitarian assistance to Burmese students along the Thai-Burma Border
  Burma: Political Situation (Statement of David F. Lambertson)
  Statement by Richard Schifter
  Testimony of Holly Burkhalter, Asia Watch
- Thra Tha Din – Translation of Tape: Conversation from Kawthoolei, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  Translation of Tape: Conversation from Kawthoolei by Ba Saw Khin, 1986
  Letter from Saw Tha Din,1981
- Stephen Thapwa, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Letters from Stephen Thapwa
- Switzerland, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  Letter from Jean-Marc Rastorfer, Director of Centre d’Etudes et de Documentation sur le Karenni
- Burmese abuse on minorities, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  News on “Burmese minorities allege abuse on slave railway”
- Bill Stevenson, 1984-1987 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Letters from Bill Stevenson
- Congressman Solomon, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Letter to Gerald Solomon, U.S. House of Representatives
  Letter from Karenni Provisional Government
  Letter to David Lonie, U.S. House of Representatives
- Senator Paul Simon, 1990-1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Letters from Paul Simon, U.S. Senator
- Hugh Wood, Karen Information Office, 1987 - 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10 A-B)
  Newsletter No. 17 of St. George’s Cathedral 1987
  Letters from Karen Information Office to Harold Klein
  Letters from people (e.g. Karen Information Office) to people
  Agreement Between the Unites States of America and Burma
- Hugh Wood, Chairman of Tribal Refugee Welfare in South East Asia / Conny Allmark, Secretary of Tribal Refugee Welfare, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 111)
  News (e.g. The Washington Post)
  Far Eastern Economic Review 1989
  Refugee Report Along The Thai-Burma Border
  SENATE 1989 pp.4330 – 4332
  News Bulletin of Tribal Refugee Welfare 1989
  News Release of Minister for Foreign Affairs and Trade 1989
  Letters from Members of Parliament of Australia
  Letter from Chris Schacht, Senator for South Australia, to Hugh Wood
- Hugh Wood, Chairman of Tribal Refugee Welfare in South East Asia / Conny Allmark, Secretary of Tribal Refugee Welfare, 1989 - 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  Statement Supporting the Pro-Democracy Movement in Burma 1989
  Letters from people (e.g. Tribal Refugee Welfare) to people
  Paper about “Yesterdays Displaced Persons Todays Refugees” by Hugh Wood
  More than Symbolic by Garry Woodard
- Miscellany, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  Letters from Hugh Wood
  Western Australian Division Media Release 1990
  Burma News Release 1991
  News (e.g. The Sydney Morning Harold)
  The Lancet Vol. 1991
  Burma Report 3rd 1991
  ASIAWEEK 1991
  Far Eastern Economic Review 1991
- Miscellany, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  Australia Burma Conference
  Resolutions for Presentation to the Government of Australia
  Media Release of Burmese Refugees
  Paper about “Promote Friendship, Strengthen Cooperation and Seek Common Development on a Mutually Beneficial Basis” by Feng Yuan Lun
- Miscellany, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  Guardian Weekly 1993
  Paper about “ Lancang River-Meikong River Economic Circle Idea” by Mr. Sun Zhiyang
  Paper about “ The Asean Response to Burmese Repression” by John McKinnon
  Letters from Karen Information Office to people
  Media Release of Christabel Chamarette
  Paper about “ Introductory Statement by the Special Rapporteur on the Situation of Human Rights in Myanmar ” by Professor Yozo Yokota 1993
- Miscellany, 1993 - 1994 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  Situations of Human Rights in Burma
  Far Eastern Economic Review 1993
  Paper about “ Mid Year Report on Burma/Burmese Border ” by Jack Dunford 1993
  Asia week 1994
  Statement by Prime Minister Dr. Sein Win of the National Coalition Government of Burma in Washington, D.C.
- Presbyterian Church, 1986 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  A Proposal by the Presbytery of Riverside to the Presbyterian Church to Establish an International Partnership with a Pahk and Pahks in Western Thailand from Kanchanaburi Northward to Mae Hong Son
  A Project Proposal for Karenni Text Book Production
  Letters from Presbyterian Committee on the Self-Development of People to Harold Klein
  Letters from Presbytery of Riverside to Harold Klein
  Letters from Presbyterian Church to Harold Klein
  Letters from First Presbyterian Church to Harold Klein
  Paper about “Address to the National Committee on the Self-Development of People” by Dr. St. Paul Epps
  Self-Development of People Criteria and Guidelines
  Paper about “ A Time for Testing”
- REAP, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  Letters from REAP International to Harold Klein
- Dan Rostenkowski, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  Letters from Harold Klein to Representative Dan Rostenkowski
- Misc. Letters, 1987 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  Letters of Saw Samson and Narong Thongsrinoon
  One Letter from Harold Klein to San Bernardino County Medical Society
- David G. Sanders, 1987 -1988 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  Letters from David G. Sanders & Associates
  A Proposal for Emergency Humanitarian Aid for Karen, Karenni and Mon Refugees
  A Proposal for the Karen National Union
- Miscellany, 1991 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  During 1987, the NDF made great achievements
  Activities in the DELTA Area and Activities on the General Public
  Letters from Embassy of the United States of America to Alpheus San Dok
- Saw San Key – Case for the Karen, 1947 - 1848 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  Copies of the booklet “ Karen and Karen State “ by Saw Po Chit, member of the Karen
  Annexure ‘A’ to the minutes of the third meeting of the Karen Affairs Sub-committee held on the 13th
- Shan Human Rights, 1991 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Letters and information from Co-Ordination Committee, Shan Human Rights Foundation to Harold Klein
  Three Reports from the Shan Sate 1991
  Letter of Thanks-Giving to all Concerned for Their Compassionate Help
  News about “Burmese Soldiers Pound Shan Rebels” by Subin Kheunkaew
  Monthly Report of Shan Human Rights Foundation
  Photographs of victims
  One Letter from Christ College Irvine to Harold Klein
- Saw Shwe Yah Hai, 1986 - 1987 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  Letters from Harold Klein to Saw Shwe Yah Hai
  Letters from Saw Shwe Yah Hai to Harold Klein
- Miscellany, 1988 - 1989 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  News from San Francisco Chronicle 1988
  Letters to and from Bruce Siegel
- Josef Silverstein, 1987 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  Letters from Josef Silverstein, the State University of New Jersey Rutgers to Harold Klein
  The Other Side of Burma’s Struggle for Independence pp.98 - 108
- Martin Smith, 1987 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Letters to and from Martin Smith
- Miscellany, 1980 – 1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  Letters from Col. Samson
  Paper about “ Memoirs of the Four-Foot Colonel “ by Gen. Smith Dun 1980
- Jean-Marc Rastorfer, 1990 – 1991 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  Letter from Jean-Marc Rastorfer
  International Council of Independent States Official Bulletin No. 9 1990 – 1991
  Collection Les Aventures Extraordinaire 1927
  DEH SEDANG Kingdom of all the Sedang
- Micah Rowley, 1986 - 1996 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  Letters from Micah Rowley
  News from Cranford Chronicle
  News from The Asian Wall Street Journal Weekly 1986
  Paper about PA-OH People by Mika Rolly
- Research Papers, 1981- 1989 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  Letters from Thray Cot Shwin to Harold Klein
  Paper about “ Bacterial Pod Rot of Leucaena Leucocephala Caused by Pseudomonas Fluorescens Biotype 2” by J.M.Lenne
  Paper about “A Wonder Tree but not a Panacea for all Reforestation Areas” by Sebastian S. Quiniones
  Paper about “Alley Cropping Maize and Leucaena in Southern Nigeria” by B.T. Kang
  Paper about “ A Farmer’s Practical Guide for Giant Leucaena ” by Kenneth A. Prussner
  A Message to my Karen Friends
- Miscellany, 1991 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  Letters to and from Ian Scott
  Stilwell’s Own Gurkhas
  One letter from Saw Htoo to Harold Klein
- Karen National Union, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  Creation of the Karen National Union, The Centrally Organized Body. Its Functional and Organizational Activities.
- Correspondence, 1983 – 1990 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  Letters between Saw Marshall Shwin, Pee Pee Emma Harold Klein
- Muslim Liberation Organization of Burma, 1988 - 1993 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  Letters from Muslim Liberation Organization of Burma
  Position of the National Democratic front Concerning the Students Who Have Arrived in the Revolutionary Areas
  The Statement of the Kawthoolet Muslim Central Organization Committee
- Mu Loh Din, 1991 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  Letters from Mu Loh Din (living in South Korea) to Harold Klein
- Nai Shwe Kyin, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  Resume of Nai Shwe Kyin (a) Nai Ba Lwin
  Speech given by Nai Shwe Kyin
- New Mon State Party, 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  Report on Activities of the New Mon State Party
  Statement on the 47th Anniversary of Mon National Day
- Narcotics--Burma, 1977 - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  World Report from IBM
  Year plan for Nacotics Control in Shan Sate 1977
  News on the Burma Military Regime’s Collaboration with Drug Business
  Burmese Government Drug Connection
  Articles about “Burma is still world’s largest opium producer”
  The Nation on Sunday Vol. 16, No45540 Bangkok
- Isaac Po, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  Paper about “There Was a Man Sent by God” by An Toe of No Boe
  Letters from Isaac Po to various people
- William H. Overholt, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  One Article “Burma: Disintegration, Drugs, Democracy” by William H. Overholt
- Overseas Burma Liberation Organization, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  Press Release from Overseas Burma Liberation Front
  Letters from Overseas Burmese Community of WA to people
  Bullshit Bulletin from Embassy of the Union of Myanmar No.5 1990
  Human Rights from Burma (Inc.) Vol. 2 No.6 1990
  Report from Overseas Burmese Democratic Community
  Burma Newsletter Vol.2, No.2 1991
  B.U.R.M.A. Vol.1, No.4 1991
- Pa-Oh Booklet (Box 4, Folder 44)
  PA-OH People by Mika Rolly
- Karen Parker, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  Letters from Karen Parker to Harold Klein
- Vegetables--Diseases Receipt, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  “Identifying Disease of Vegetables”
- Communiqué from Burma, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  “ A Communiqué from Burma”
- Correspondence, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  One letter from Patrick San Hoo, Secretary of Karenni Refugees Committee, to Harold Klein
  One letter from Harold Klein to H. Ross Perot
- Senator Claiborne Pell, 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  Letters from Senator Claiborne Pell to Harold Klein
  Letters from Harold Klein to Senator Claiborne Pell
  Statement by U Mya Than, Deputy Permanent Representative at the Meeting of the Working Group on Indigenous Populations on 2 August 1988
  S.CON.RES.139 100th Congress 2d Session
- News and Correspondence, 1986 – 1993 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  Letters from Lawrence Po
  News about “Karens may join communist fold” by Suthep Chaiviwan
  Asiaweek, September 2, 1988
  Photographs
- National Archives, 1985 -1986 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  Letters from National Archives to Harold Klein
  The Records Reproduced in the Microfilm Publication are from General Records of the Department of State Record Group 59
- Health, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  Letters to National Council for Int. Health
  International Health News Vol.8, No. 1 1987
- Miscellany, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  Burma: Towards an international campaign 1990
- Senator Sam Nunn, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  Letters to and from Senator Sam Nunn
- Terrorism News Briefing, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  Special News Briefing
- Correspondence, 1989-1992 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  One letter from Cherry O’ Byaw to Harold Klein
  One letter from Stephen O’Connell to Harold Klein
- Miscellany, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  Notes from Meeting at the Swedish Foreign Office
  Letters from Harold Klein to Bo Olson
  Press Release from Ministry for Foreign Affairs
  Letters from people (e.g. Sweden Democratic Burma, Permanent Representative for Sweden to the United Nations, and …) to Harold Klein Conference Denouncing SLORC’s Sham National Convention 1993
  Position of the National Council of the Union of Burma (NCUB) on Internal Peace
  Summary Report “The Sweden-Democratic Burma Friendship Association's Involvement with RFB and DVB
- Miscellany, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  Confidential “Conversation of H.E.Klein with Stuart Power Concerning OSS/Detachment 101 Proposal to Build a School in Lashio Burma”
  A Proposal School of Agriculture, Forestry, and Vocational Training for the Highland Peoples of Myanmar by the Veterans of OSS Detachment 101
  The Dallas Morning News “Veteran Leads Effort to Build School for Ex-allies in Burma” 1993
- Maldon Institute Risk Analysis, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  Burma: A Political Risk Analysis 1988 The Maldon Institute
- Miscellany, 1987 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  Letters from people (e.g. The Government of Kawthoolei, The Karen National Union, and …) to Harold Klein
  Situation Report from the Karen National Union 1991
  Media Release of the Karen National Union 1992
  Written Statement by Dr. Em Marta, Representative of International Work Group for Indigenous Affairs
  Oral Intervention by Dr. Em Marta
  A Statement by International Work Group for Indigenous Affairs
  Question of the Violation of Human Rights and Fundamental Freedoms in any Part of the World, with Particular Reference to Colonial and Other Dependent Countries and Territories
- Miscellany, 1988 - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  “Leadville to LHASA CIA Trains Tibetan Freedom Fighters in Colorado’s Mining County” by Steve McNallen
  One Letter from the Karen National Union to Harold Klein
  Inside Burma “The Isolated Nation of Burma"
- Miscellany, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  “Thai-Burma Anti-Drug Proposal Gets a Boost” by Thana Poopat
  Letters from South East Asian Institute for Uplands Development to people
- Miscellany, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  “A Silent Revolution Fought by Unsung Warriors” by Barbara Crossette 1987
  Special Report: Accounts of Burmese Military Human Rights Abuse in Tenasserim Area, 1983 – 1986
  Project Maje: Report on the Project’s First Year, June 1986 to May 1987
  Human Rights Survey 1987
  “Ethnic Minorities of the Burma Frontiers and Their Resistance Groups” by Edith T. Mirante
  Edith T. Mirante, 1987, Burma Frontier Insurgency, Project Maje
  Report of a Survey on Human Rights Abuse in Frontier Areas of Burma, 1986 - 1987
- Miscellany, 1988 - 1990 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Letters from Project Maje to Harold Klein
  Statement of the Croup Condemning the Mass Killings Mass Arrests, and Denial of Human Rights in Burma 1988
  1988 Air Force Association Convention Opening Address
  Speech by Edith T. Mirante at Freedom for Burma Demonstration in New York City 1988
  Women Speak Out for Peace in Burma 1989 Project Maje
  “Burmese Military is Forcing Mass Migration from Cities” by Steven Erlanger
  “Hostages to Tourism” by Edith T. Mirante
- Miscellany, 1988 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  “Recent Accounts of Burmese Military Human Rights Abuse in the Shan State” 1988 Project Maje
  “People under Threat but Church Grows” 1990 Partners Vol.6, No.3
  “Out Journey” Voices from Arakan, Western Burma, 1991, Project Maje
  News from International Affairs, Asiaweek
- Dawn News Bulletin, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Dawn News Bulletin No. 13-15, No. 24, 1989
- Dawn News Bulletin, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  Dawn News Bulletin Vol. 1. No. 1, 1990
  Dawn News Bulletin Vol. 1. No. 1-6, 1990
  Dawn News Bulletin Vol. 2, No. 9-11, No. 14-15, No. 17-18, No. 19-21, No. 23-24, 1990
- Dawn News Bulletin, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Dawn News Bulletin Vol. 2. No. 25-26, 1991
  Dawn News Bulletin Vol. 3. No. 2, 3, 5, 6, 10, 1991
- Karenni Journal, 1987 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Letters from Karenni Provisional Government to Harold Klein
  The Karenni Journal Serial No. 3-5, 7-11, 1987
  The Karenni Journal Serial No. 16, 1990
  The Karenni Journal Serial No. 1-2, 1991
- Karenni Provisional Government, 1990 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  The Karenni Journal Serial No. 3-4, 1991
  The Formation of the United Karenni Independent States 1946
  Report “ The Allegation, The British Betrayal of Trust”
  Report from Karenni Provisional Government 1990-1991
  Report “Burma in 1947. An Political Intrigue, Duplicity, Fabrication, Complicity and the Rape of Karenni” by Ministry of Foreign Affairs of Karenni Provisional Government
  A Copy of Stamps 1986 -1991
  A Statement by the Karenni Provisional Government Presented to the United Nations, New York 1991
- Miscellany, 1991-1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Stamps
  Letters from people (e.g. Karenni Provisional Government) to Harold Klein
  Receipts for Certified Mail
  Professor John Dwyer Medical Report
  Report “ Military Operations: What is legal and what is illegal in light of international humanitarian law” by Karen Parker 1984
  Report “Karen legal issues” from Karen Parker and Christopher Cline to Mr. Abel Tweed, Foreign Minister of Karenni Provisional Government 1992
  Statements by Karenni Refugees 1992
- Miscellany, 1991 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Letters from people in the Government of Karenni to Harold Klein
  Report “Announcing Micro-Hydropower Sourcebook”
  Report “The Karenni Case Studies” by Government of Karenni
- ABC News, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Letters from Harold Klein to ABC News
- Saw Lay Wee, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  One letter from Saw Lay Wee to Harold Klein
- Kayella A. Leighton (Box 5, Folder 13)
  One letter from Kayella A. Leighton to Harold Klein
- Saw Lincoln, 1990 - 1991 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Letters to and from Saw Lincoln
  Letter from Karen Rural Development Center
- Senator Bill Leonard, 1991 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Letters from Senator Bill Leonard to Harold Klein
  Report “Garamendi’s Two Little Words” by Sacramento Bee
  Letters from Harold Klein to Senator Leonard
- Rep. Jerry Lewis, 1987 - 1993 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Letters to and from Representative Jerry Lewis
- Burton Levin, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  “Democracy and Dissent: The Outlook for Burma” A talk by Burton Levin, U.S. Ambassador to Burma, 1988
- Lard Listowel, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Report “Lard Listowel: Damage to Burma’s Reputation” by the Karen People of Burma
- Bertil Lintner, 1987 - 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Letters from Bertil Lintner to various people
- Miscellany, 1984 - 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  Letters from people (e.g. Salween Relief Fund) to Harold Klein
  News ‘Just Say No’ – Sometimes by Kenneth E. Sharpe
  March 31, 1988 N.Y. Times “U.S. Asking China’s Help on Burmese Drugs” by Barbara Crossette
- U.P. Los Banos, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  One Letter from University of the Philippines at Los Banos to Harold Klein
- Miscellany, 2006 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  Letter from Klein to Jeffrey Pertersen of Echols Collection, Cornell
  Photo: Myanmar Rights Abuse
  Other Photos
- AKA Proposals, 1987 - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  AKA Proposal for Operation Recovery
  Note for Karen New Year – Bakers Field